## **SHALU SHALU**

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

UI/UX designer with a professional background as an Assistant and Web designer experienced in web and mobile applications including product design within various industries. Passionate in designing products and applications according to the user's needs and experience and making human-centred designs aesthetical and simple.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE (4 YEARS)**

### UI/UX Designer, 03/2022 to Current Gift Canadian - Toronto, ON

- Collaborated with teammates to deliver valuable features meeting business and customer needs.
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Collaborated with UX teams to integrate UI features complying with prescribed code standards and technical design guidelines.
- Engineered prototypes to support research and usability testing.

## **UX/UI Designer,** 11/2021 to 07/2022 **Academy projects** - Toronto, ON

#### Financial group

Fintech app that helps people to manage their budgets. The user could get cash back on daily shopping and track their fund transactions of regular expenses.

- Researched user problems and analyzed their pain points, and competitive analysis, and created user stories.
- Understanding user pain points, created user-centric design solution and prepared a User flow diagram.
- Created low-fidelity wireframes with user-centric solutions on papers and prepared digitized wireframes with UI design principles and had given them for user testing.
- After user feedback applied the iterations and created high-fidelity wireframes and prepared a responsive design and mockup.

Tools: Figma, photoshop, creative cloud

Yummy Tummy

#### CONTACT

Address: Toronto, Canada M3C 1S6

Phone: 416 821 4390

Email: shaluoad97@gmail.com

## WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://www.behance.net /Shaluoad 90
- https://www.linkedin.com /in/shalu0907/
- https://shaluportfoliowebsite.github. io/Shaluportfoliowebsite/index.html

#### SKILLS

- · User research, user persona
- · Information Architecture, Sitemap
- Design UI design patterns
- Building UI design system, components
- User research, competitive analysis
- Product design, User flow diagram,
   Wireframes
- · Building Cohesive brand
- · Style guide, Responsive designs
- Prototyping (Marvel, Invision)
- Usability and A/B testing and iteration
- Final designs, Mockups
- User Interface Design
- UI animation
- · Html, Css and Java script

**TOOLS** 

Recipe web application for everyone! It gives access to online grocery shopping at home easily. Provides simple, delicious, customizable recipes with built-in shopping list for your convenience.

- Researched user requirements worked on UX Lean and worked at UCD (User Centered designs), Human-Computer Interaction.
- Conducted user's interviews, worked on User personas and analyzed User problems and found solutions.
- Created user flow diagram and wireframe from low to high fidelity.
   Created style guide and applied User Interfaces.
- Usability testing(Rapid prototyping testing) and iterations
- Created final designs and mockups

Tools: Sketch, Marvel

### Assistant Designer, 12/2014 to 08/2017 Jarviz Infosec Pvt Ltd - Gurugram, India

#### **MobileSOS**

A women's safety application with unique functions such as "Shake your Device" without getting noticed in an emergency to contact near and dear ones.

- Created wireframes from low to high fidelity according to the product requirement, applied visual design and created prototypes.
- Engineered prototypes to support research and usability testing.
   Collaborated with teammates to deliver valuable features meeting business and customer needs.

Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

#### MobileHeal Pro

Offers advanced safety and security to Android smartphones and services like managing your data from mobile to desktop, finding your phone, and data recovery.

- Created icons and UI elements for the User Interface including a style guide and applied it to the responsive designs.
- Collaborated with developers and the Ux team and worked on rapid prototyping and usability tests.

Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

# Web Designer, 07/2014 to 11/2014 Antheia infrastructure pvt ltd - Gurugram, , India

#### www.propchill.com

It was a real estate website development project where users could buy/sell/rent properties.

 Worked on front-end development using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and Bootstrap. Figma

Sketch

Photoshop

Illustrator

Prototype (Invision, Marvel)

Wireframe( Balsamiq)

Atom

GitHub

Flinto

#### EDUCATION

Cartificate in UI Designer, 08/2022

Careerfoundry - Toronto, ON

Specialization in Mobile and Web
application

Master of Science, Master in Computer
Application, 06/2014
Rajasthan Technical University - Kota,
India

Bachelor of Science, Computer
Applications Development, 08/2011
Bachelor in Computer Application India

prove user experie	nce			
			-	

 $\bullet$  Collaborated with the team, Identified and eliminated website bugs to